<story-context id="story-11.8-cicd-pipeline-integration" v="1.0">
  <metadata>
    <epicId>11</epicId>
    <storyId>11.8</storyId>
    <title>CI/CD Pipeline Integration</title>
    <status>drafted</status>
    <generatedAt>2025-10-31</generatedAt>
    <generator>BMAD Story Context Workflow</generator>
    <sourceStoryPath>docs/stories/story-11.8-cicd-pipeline-integration.md</sourceStoryPath>
  </metadata>

  <story>
    <asA>development team member</asA>
    <iWant>comprehensive CI/CD pipeline integration for the professional testing architecture</iWant>
    <soThat>quality gates are enforced automatically and testing infrastructure scales seamlessly across development workflows</soThat>
    <tasks>
      - CI/CD Configuration Setup (AC: 1): Configure automated NMEA Bridge Simulator lifecycle management, implement parallel test execution without port/resource conflicts, add flaky test detection with configurable retry logic, create test environment cleanup scripts for CI runs
      - Quality Gates Implementation (AC: 2): Configure coverage threshold enforcement in pipeline, implement performance regression detection with build failures, add marine safety compliance validation checks, set up automated quality report generation  
      - Pipeline Performance Optimization (AC: 3): Implement selective test running based on changed files, optimize resource usage for CI environments (memory, CPU), add test result caching for faster incremental builds, configure failure analysis and debugging artifacts
    </tasks>
  </story>

  <acceptanceCriteria>
    1. CI/CD Pipeline Configuration: Automated NMEA Bridge Simulator startup/shutdown management implemented, parallel test execution support without resource conflicts configured, flaky test detection and automatic retry mechanisms operational, test environment cleanup and state reset between runs automated
    2. Quality Gate Integration: Coverage threshold enforcement in build pipeline (70% global, 85% widgets, 80% services, 90% integration), performance threshold validation with build failure on regression (&lt;16ms renders, &lt;100ms latency, &lt;50MB memory), marine safety requirement compliance validation integrated, automated quality report generation and distribution functional
    3. Pipeline Optimization: Test execution time optimization with selective test running implemented, resource utilization optimization for CI/CD environments configured, test result caching and incremental validation operational, failure analysis and debugging support integration available
  </acceptanceCriteria>

  <artifacts>
    <docs>
      <doc>
        <path>docs/tech-spec-epic-11.md</path>
        <title>Technical Specification: Epic 11 - Professional-Grade Testing Architecture</title>
        <section>Story 11.8: CI/CD Pipeline Integration</section>
        <snippet>Epic 11 establishes a unified professional-grade testing architecture that transforms existing 228+ test files from basic validation to comprehensive requirement verification using the sophisticated NMEA Bridge Simulator infrastructure built in Epic 7 and enhanced in Epic 10.</snippet>
      </doc>
      <doc>
        <path>docs/stories/epic-11-professional-grade-testing-architecture.md</path>
        <title>Epic 11: Professional-Grade Testing Architecture</title>
        <section>Story 11.8: CI/CD Pipeline Integration</section>
        <snippet>Integrate professional testing architecture with continuous integration and deployment pipeline. Deliverables include automated NMEA Bridge Simulator startup/shutdown management, quality gate integration with coverage and performance thresholds, and pipeline optimization.</snippet>
      </doc>
      <doc>
        <path>docs/architecture.md</path>
        <title>Boating Instruments App Fullstack Architecture Document</title>
        <section>Epic 11 Testing Architecture Foundation</section>
        <snippet>Unified NMEA Bridge Simulator Integration for professional-grade testing leveraging Epic 7/10 simulator infrastructure with triple testing strategy and quality standards framework enforcing performance thresholds and coverage requirements.</snippet>
      </doc>
      <doc>
        <path>bmad/bmm/workflows/testarch/trace/instructions.md</path>
        <title>Test Architect Workflow: Requirements Traceability & Quality Gate Decision</title>
        <section>Quality Gate Decision Engine</section>
        <snippet>Phase 2 uses traceability results to make quality gate decisions (PASS/CONCERNS/FAIL/WAIVED) based on evidence and decision rules. Deterministic rule-based approach with thresholds for P0/P1 coverage, pass rates, and marine safety compliance.</snippet>
      </doc>
      <doc>
        <path>docs/nmea-bridge-simulator-architecture.md</path>
        <title>NMEA Bridge Simulator Architecture</title>
        <section>Continuous Integration Integration</section>
        <snippet>CI/CD integration with Docker-based simulator for automated testing pipelines. REST API control interface on port 9090 for scenario management, real-time control, and session management.</snippet>
      </doc>
      <doc>
        <path>TESTING-STRATEGY.md</path>
        <title>Boating Instruments App - Testing Strategy</title>
        <section>Quality Gates</section>
        <snippet>Pre-release quality gates include 100% test pass rate, coverage ≥70% sustained, 99.5% crash-free rate (2 weeks sustained), and performance benchmarks pass.</snippet>
      </doc>
    </docs>
    <code>
      <artifact>
        <path>.github/workflows/ci-full.yml</path>
        <kind>workflow</kind>
        <symbol>CI - Full Tests</symbol>
        <lines>1-50</lines>
        <reason>Existing full CI pipeline that needs integration with professional testing architecture</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>.github/workflows/ci-fast.yml</path>
        <kind>workflow</kind>
        <symbol>CI - Fast Tests</symbol>
        <lines>1-50</lines>
        <reason>Fast CI pipeline for PRs that needs quality gate integration</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>.github/workflows/simulator-control-integration-tests.yml</path>
        <kind>workflow</kind>
        <symbol>Simulator Control API Integration Tests</symbol>
        <lines>1-100</lines>
        <reason>Existing simulator integration testing pipeline to extend with quality gates</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>boatingInstrumentsApp/package.json</path>
        <kind>config</kind>
        <symbol>test scripts</symbol>
        <lines>12-32</lines>
        <reason>Existing test scripts including quality gates, coverage thresholds, and performance validation</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>boatingInstrumentsApp/server/nmea-bridge-simulator.js</path>
        <kind>service</kind>
        <symbol>NMEABridgeSimulator</symbol>
        <lines>32-50</lines>
        <reason>NMEA Bridge Simulator that needs automated lifecycle management in CI/CD</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>boatingInstrumentsApp/__tests__/nmea-bridge-simulator-integration.test.ts</path>
        <kind>test</kind>
        <symbol>simulator integration tests</symbol>
        <lines>88-100</lines>
        <reason>Performance and integration tests that validate 500+ messages/second and marine safety thresholds</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>boatingInstrumentsApp/__tests__/nmea-bridge-simulator-network.test.ts</path>
        <kind>test</kind>
        <symbol>network integration tests</symbol>
        <lines>27-50</lines>
        <reason>Real network integration tests showing simulator startup/shutdown patterns for CI automation</reason>
      </artifact>
    </code>
    <dependencies>
      <node>
        <jest>^29.0.0</jest>
        <react-native-testing-library>^13.3.3</react-native-testing-library>
        <websocket>^1.0.35</websocket>
      </node>
    </dependencies>
  </artifacts>

  <constraints>
    - NMEA Bridge Simulator Integration: Must leverage Epic 7/10 simulator infrastructure with reliable startup/shutdown automation on ports 9090 (API), 8080 (WebSocket), 2000 (TCP)
    - Quality Threshold Framework: Enforce coverage thresholds (70%+ global, 85% widgets, 80% services, 90% integration) and performance thresholds (&lt;16ms renders, &lt;100ms latency, &lt;50MB memory) established in Story 11.6
    - Multi-Platform Support: CI/CD must support web development workflow and native platform testing consistently across iOS, Android, Windows, macOS platforms
    - Marine Safety Compliance: &lt;100ms NMEA sentence → widget update enforced in CI, 99.5% crash-free rate validation, comprehensive error condition testing for safety-critical operations
    - Professional Testing Standards: All tests must include PURPOSE/REQUIREMENT/METHOD documentation headers established in Story 11.4
    - Architecture Alignment: Respect Epic 6 domain-separated service boundaries (navigation, engine, environment, autopilot, core) in testing infrastructure
  </constraints>
  
  <interfaces>
    <interface>
      <name>NMEA Bridge Simulator Control API</name>
      <kind>REST endpoint</kind>
      <signature>POST /api/scenarios/start, GET /api/scenarios/status, POST /api/scenarios/stop, POST /api/inject-data, GET /api/metrics/performance</signature>
      <path>boatingInstrumentsApp/server/nmea-bridge-simulator.js</path>
    </interface>
    <interface>
      <name>GitHub Actions Workflow</name>
      <kind>CI/CD pipeline</kind>
      <signature>CI workflow with simulator lifecycle, quality gates, and performance validation</signature>
      <path>.github/workflows/</path>
    </interface>
    <interface>
      <name>Jest Coverage API</name>
      <kind>test framework</kind>
      <signature>--coverage --coverageReporters=json-summary --passWithNoTests</signature>
      <path>boatingInstrumentsApp/package.json</path>
    </interface>
    <interface>
      <name>Quality Gate Enforcer</name>
      <kind>script interface</kind>
      <signature>node scripts/quality-gate-enforcer.js</signature>
      <path>boatingInstrumentsApp/scripts/quality-gate-enforcer.js</path>
    </interface>
  </interfaces>
  
  <tests>
    <standards>Professional testing architecture established in Epic 11 with triple testing strategy (Static Mocks, API Message Injection, Full Scenario Integration). All tests must include PURPOSE/REQUIREMENT/METHOD documentation headers and maintain marine domain validation standards with 0.1 nautical mile GPS precision, 0.1 unit depth accuracy, and &lt;1° wind directional precision. Performance targets: &lt;50ms unit tests, &lt;2000ms integration tests, &lt;30 seconds E2E tests.</standards>
    <locations>__tests__/tier1-unit/, __tests__/tier2-integration/, __tests__/tier3-e2e/, __tests__/marine-safety/, marine-assets/test-scenarios/epic-11-widget-testing/</locations>
    <ideas>
      AC1 Tests: Simulator lifecycle automation test (startup/shutdown in CI), parallel execution conflict detection test, flaky test retry mechanism validation, test environment cleanup verification
      AC2 Tests: Coverage threshold enforcement test (build failure on &lt;70% global), performance regression detection test (&gt;16ms render failure), marine safety compliance validation test (99.5% crash-free rate), quality report generation automation test
      AC3 Tests: Selective test running performance test (changed files only), CI resource utilization monitoring test (&lt;2GB memory, &lt;4 CPU cores), test result caching effectiveness test, failure analysis artifact collection test
    </ideas>
  </tests>
</story-context>